Guide to the Aris Phillips Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Aris Phillips papers
1948-1978
MS 1606
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
1.5
(4 boxes)
The papers consist of grant and proposal files, subject files, and Yale University files.
Phillips, A. (Aris)
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Mrs. Bessie Phillips, 1991.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The Aris Phillips papers, which date from 1948 to 1978, consist primarily of correspondence, proposals, and financial reports documenting the government grants in which Phillips participated. Also included are conference material and printed matter of the American Society of Mechanical Engineers (ASME). Correspondence, memoranda, and printed material pertaining to the Yale University Department of Engineering and Applied Science complete the collection.
The papers were the gift of Bessie Phillips in 1991.
Mechanical engineering; Phillips, A. (Aris); Yale University -- Faculty; Yale University. Dept. of Engineering and Applied Science
- Inventory
  - Grants and proposals
    - "Mechanics of the Esophagus," proposal for Department of Health, Education, and Welfare, 1970-1975 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - "Cyclic Plasticity of Metals," research proposal submitted to the National Science Foundation; reviewed by Aris Phillips, 1975 January (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - National Science Founation (NSF) Grant G-2960: financial reports, 1956-1960 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - National Science Foundation Grant G-19221: financial reports, 1961-1964 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - National Science Foundation graduate traineeships, 1967, 1968, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - National Science Foundation proposal rating sheets, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Office of Naval Research (ONR): proposals and interim reports, 1950-1963, undated (Box 1, Folder 7 - 9)
    - Government contract N6-ONR-251 Task XI: correspondence, 1948-1954, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Government contract N6-ONR-251 Task XI: quarterly reports, 1948-1954 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Government contract ONR-609 12: financial reports, 1955-1964 (Box 2, Folder 12 - 13)
    - "Experimental Determination of Corners in the Yield Surface," by Aris Phillips and George A. Gray, ONR-609-12, 1958 December (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Office of Ordnance Research, U.S. Army, 1956-1959, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - "Inelastic Constitutive Equations with Measures of Internal Change," Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute research proposal, 1976 May (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - American Society of Mechanical Engineers (ASME): Joint Applied Mechanics and Fluids Engineering Conference, 1977 June (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - American Society of Mechanical Engineers (ASME): manuals, 1966, 1971, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Ford Foundation loans: policy matters, 1962-1969 (Box 2, Folder 19 - 22)
  - Ph.D. Program in Engineering at the University of New Hampshire: general files, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Ph.D. Program in Engineering at the University of New Hampshire: proposals, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Publishers, 1948-1962 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Stanford University: faculty and executive committee minutes for School of Engineering, 1949-1954, undated (Box 3, Folder 26 - 27)
  - Yale University
    - Engineering and Applied Science Library, Becton, and Kline Science Library, 1976-1978, undated (Box 3, Folder 28 - 31)
    - Department of Engineering and Applied Science: M.D.-Ph.D. Program, 1968-1969 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Masters Program for Practising Engineers, 1968-1969, undated (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - MTS machine, 1970, undated (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Vehicular Traffic Flow and Control - Theories, Experiments and Applications, Yale summer course, 1965 December-1966 October (Box 4, Folder 35 - 36)
    - Yale Science and Engineering Association (YSEA), 1974-1977 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Biographical information (in Greek with English translation), 1995 (Box 4, Folder 38)